Guide to the Naomi Shihab Nye Papers
The Wittliff Collections
- Works, 1963-2017; 30 boxes
  - Poems, circa 1970s - circa 2010s
    - N (Box 8, Folder 15)
      "Necessity Is Only 8 Miles Away," "Necklace," "Needing Basketball," "Negotiations with a Volcano," "The Net," "New Skills," "New Year's Eve was a 4 sleeping bag night," "The News," "Nez Perce," "Niagara," "Night Shift," "Nine Years Later (remembering William Stafford)," "No Limit," "No Souvenirs," "No Wonder," "Nobody's Newspaper," "North Carolina," "Not Gone-For Rusty," "Not Knowing," "Notes From the Dream Journal of a Light Sleeper."
    - O (Box 9, Folder 1)
      "Oats," "Ocean," "The Ocean of Hope," "October, California," "Office 337, Wheeler Hall, Berkeley," "Old Crying," "Old Days," "The Old Friend Has Longer Hair," "Old Friends," "Old Man in Canada," "The old man stood in his suit and said," "The Old Yellow Chair," "Olive Jar," "Olive Skin, Olive Bones," "On a hot humid summer evening in a small town in south Texas," "On Being the Daughter," "On Counting Chickens," "On Learning My Childhood Best Friend Became an Unwed Mother," "On Moving Bruce Cunningham's Blank Canvases, Longview TX. Sept 10, 1974," "On My Way to the Reading of Poems," "On Overhearing a Teacher Say, 'So What if the Arabs had Israel before the Jews Took Over, They Weren't Doing a Damn Thing with It'," "On Receiving a Note from My Editor which Called a Certain Poem Dimwitted," "On the Canadian National Railroad," "On the Road to Chichicastenango," "On This Side of the World," "Once at a stoplight I saw my old best friend," "One Boy Told Me," "One Difference," "One Island," "One Man's Way," "One of a Kind," "One of the things that I wonder about is," "One Way or the Other," "The Only Necessary Profession," "Open Wide," "Our Best Selves," "Our Friend Tonio," "Out There," "Out West," "Over the Fence."
    - P (Box 9, Folder 2)
      "A Pacifist Declares War at the Mercedes Dealer," "Pacify," "The Palace Cafe, Shiner, Texas," "Pakistan with Open Arms," "A Palestinian Might Say," "Papaya," "Parade," "Parking Lot," "Parts," "Passing the Seminary Cemetery on the Way to the Airport," "Password," "Peter Pan Man Poem," "Phone Number Written on a Leaf," "Photograph - for my parents," "Pictures from the Village," "Pilgrimage," "Pioneers," "Plans," "Pocket - for Bob Bonazzi," "Pockets," "a poem again," "Poem for Nancy and Lou," "The Poem I Never Write," "The Poem Lives in a Small House," "Poem to D.C.," "A poem to Dubby who always seems to think that everybody else has a whole lot going on," "A Poem to Janice & all the Miriams," "A Poem to Liberation," "A Poem Triggered by Something in a Newspaper or Magazine," "Poetry for Dinner," "Polar Bear," "The Political Luncheon," "Porch," "Possible," "Praise and Worship," "Prayer in My Boot," "Pull Up a Chair - in memory of Omar Sharif, d.2015 and Aziz Shihab, d. 2007," "Putting the Dog to Sleep."
    - Q-R (Box 9, Folder 3)
      "Questions One Might Ask Upon Leaving Haystack - To Stuart, from Naomi," "A quiet nineteenth spring," "Quilting Class," "Quilts," "The Radiance of Waves - for Harryette Mullen," "Rain," "Realizing Exactly What Happened at One O'Clock in the Morning," "Remembered," "The Rider," "Rinse," "Riviera Beach, Texas & My Twenty-Third Birthday," "Road Test," "The Road to Aleppo," "Rock," "Rock and Roll Thanksgiving," "Room," Rose," "The Round Window Waits with its Eye Half Open," "Roy Perez is Holding His Head Up Today," "R.S.V.P.," "Rudolf Staffel" "Rumors of a Crowd."
    - Salmon-Some (Box 9, Folder 4)
      "Salmon River in the Rain," "San Antonio," "San Antonio Song," "Santa Barbara," "Santa Fe," "Saving Half a Rainbow," "Saying So - for Chula," "A School in Jerusalem," "School bell," "Seaside Memorial Park, Corpus Christi, Texas," "Second-to-Last Words," "Secrets of Housekeeping," "Sedona Inspirational Hymn," "Senor de la Basura Dios te Mira," "Shelbyville," "The Shiner Museum (Shiner, Texas)," "Shoo-fly Pie," "Shrine of Hair," "Shrines," "Signs," "The Silence of Hutchinson, Kansas: A Letter from Texas," "Silent night in the forest," "The Silver Cart," "Simon Dreams of Africa," "Simple Life," "Simple Tastes," "Singing Myself Awake," "Sitti Speaks with the Angels," "Skins," "Sleeping and Waking," "Slump," "The Small Vases from Hebron," "Smoke," "The smudge is smoke rising," "Snow," "Soap Does Not Have Supernatural Powers - for Adlai," "Soft Returns - for my mother," "solitude the teacher," "Some Days," "Some Days I Wish I Had Been Born," "Some Poems That I Picked Off a Bunch Of Grapes," "Some Relief to Think of Stars."
    - Somebody-Swimmer (Box 9, Folder 5)
      "Somebody's Story," "'Someday," he said, 'we will all float down the Potomac,'" "Someone is Standing on the Roof of the World," "Sometimes," "Sometimes driving across the expanses of the western United States," "Sometimes I Know Why Jack Kerouac Drank and Then Sometimes I Drink - Mark Rasette," "Sometimes I Pretend," "'Sometimes If You Stir the Water Around It Revives Them'," "Somewhere in the Greens," "The Song," "South Main," "A Specific Poem for Edna, Texas, May 21, 1979," "Speechless - for David," "Sphinx," "A Spider in the Honey Bun Machine," "Spruce Street, Berkeley – for Dolores & Josh," "Staggering around the Old Familiar Room," "Stay," "Staying Close," "steeped in morning onder, i sit at a long table of books and do not want to study - or - tea," "St. Louis," "Still Waiting for a Dull Moment," "The Stolen Camera," "The Strategy of Silence," "The Street Sweeper Dies in Comanche," "Streets," "Stretched with taut unsleeping, I lie awake," "Suburban," "Sunday Newspaper August 6, 1995," "Sunday Walk, Richmond," "Sure," "A Survey of Breads in Popayan, Colombia," "Swerve, for Patty & Vince Wixon," "Swimmer, Blessed Sea."
    - T Train-Time (Box 9, Folder 6)
      "T Train," "Table for One," "Take-Off Poem," "Talking Forever – for Palestine and Dareen Tatour," "Tasting Your Food," "Tea Seller, Rajasthan," "Ted Kooser Is My President," "Telephone," "The Telling of Time," "Texas Cavaliers Cancel River Parade," "Texas Grill, Thanksgiving Eve," "Texas in the Old Days," "Texas, the First Time," "Thank You," "That Skinny Tip of Land," "There Is a Box in my Closet Full of Hugging," "There is a Huge, Dead Raccoon Under the Boat Get it Out and Why?," "There Is, in Each of Us," "There is a place where every day has a crown," "There is magic in this scrubbed land," "There is the worry of a mother who hears her son," "There Should Be a Suggestion of Firmness in the Cooked Poetry," "These Days," "Think of You I'll Think of Me," "Thinking About Cows at Ten O'Clock in the Morning, Abilene," "This Green - with respect to Federico Garcia Lorca," "This Is My Solemn Vow," "This Little Arm," "This Much Sun," "This Restaurant Where I Work," "This Solid Cat," "This Tree," "Those Precious Early Years," "Thread," "Three Mule Deer, Dusk, Organ Mountains," "Through the Kitchen Window, Chiapas," "Thunder," "The Time," "Time to go to bed but once again I pull out a piece of white paper."
    - To-Two (Box 9, Folder 7)
      "To a field," "To Free that Ache," "To Love You," "To Marc who said, "Constantly in the Company," "To My Texas Handbook," "To One Now Grown," "To Saint Christopher and Dave from Sunday Roller," "To the People Who Keep Showing Up," "To the Person Who Sent Me My First Piece of Hate Mail (Which Arrived on Valentine's Day) or Thanks A Lot," "To the Tree Frogs Outside the Window," "Today Jude Went to Heaven," "Today while standing in a post office that never," "Touring the Old Neighborhood," "Toys on the Planet Earth," "Trade," "Tranquil Desperation," "The Trashpickers, Madison Street," "The Traveling Onion," "Trouble with the Stars & Stripes," "The True Picture," "Trying to Name What Doesn't Change," "Tundra," "Tuba," "The Tunnel of Question," "Twelve O'clock at the Local Coffee Shop - for Charlie Busch," "2 a.m.," "Two Countries," "Two Hours North of the Border."
    - U-V (Box 9, Folder 8)
      "An Unobscure Wise Poem for William Blake," "Up in the middle of the night & so very unfree of my body," "An Ushering Poem for All Ushers Everywhere," "Valentine for Ernest Mann," "Vocabulary of a Hen," "A Voice in the Restaurant," "Voices."
    - Walking-When (Box 9, Folder 9)
      "Walking Down Blanco Road at Midnight," "Walking Downtown," "War," "Washing Clothes," "Watching Mothers at the Laundromat Cross Their Legs, Left Over Right," "Watching People Through Lighted Windows Eating Dinner," "Watching You When You're Not Looking," "The Way They Drive in Mexico," "We All Hail to Thee and Thy Name Forever," "We Who Are Expecting Nothing," "We will keep our freshness with us," "Wedding Cake," "A Week Before the Election," "The West Side, San Antonio, 1981," "Westbound," "What Am I to Think," "'What are you-all doing in that corner?,'" "What Are You Doing for Your Country (For the boys at Um-al-Hussein Orphanage, Jordan)," "What Brings Us Out," "What Gertrude Stein Felt When She Walked Through a Doorway," "What Happened to the Air," "What Has Been Done to Women," ""What Have You Done All Day?' Question 'Not a Damn Thing' Mr. E.K. Flach, ranchman, Sisterdale, Texas," "What He Said to His Enemies," "What I Like," "What Is It in Breaking Up," "What People Do," "What She Knew," "What She Wants," "What We Expect," "What We Will Say to One Another," "What Will Happen?" "What's Wrong with Us?" "When I was a little kid about ten years ago," "When I Was Little," "When Something You Love Dies," "When the Flag is Raised - for Judith McPheron," "When the Mission Is Not a Success," "When You Appear in a Dream - for Bill Stafford," "When you wake up."
    - Where-Wrong (Box 9, Folder 10)
      "Where did it come from?," "Wherever I Am, It's Not Here," "Wherever We Go, We Come to This," "While I Was in Canada, I Dreamed of You Once," "While in Victoria Texas for the Armadillo Race - for C.B.," "While Standing on the Edge of the Guadalupe River," "While Wandering Through Restaurant Supply Houses June 1975," "White Hair," "White Hair Over the Rocky Mountains," "Who?," "Whoever Art Was Sleeping With, It Wasn't Me," "Why, at the Age of Twenty-Three, I Am Still Not a Ski Sweater?," "Why I Am Looking at You This Way," "Why I Am Looking at You This Way," "Why I Don't Eat Much Anymore," "Why Terri Keeps Losing Things - for Teresa Anderson," "Why We Go to the Farms," "Why You Don't See Me Anymore," "Wide World," "Window Waits with its Eye Half Open," "A Woman Who Talks with Angels - for my grandmother, north of Jerusalem," "The Woman who Wrote Letters," "Women Licking Their Wounds," "Wondering About What I Do Every Day," "Wood," "The Word for Missing Rio," "Working at the Physical Fitness Club in the Lunch Bar," "Working for Tom," "The World in Translation," "The World, Starring You," "The World We Are In," "The World's Highest Passenger Railway," "Words," "Worry," "Wrong."
    - Y (Box 9, Folder 11)
      "Yellow Glove," "Yes," "You," "You Are a Quiet Song," "You Are Not at Home," "You Can't Fool Me," "You sit in my yard like the Sphinx of ancient Egypt," "Your Name," "Your Weight, at Birth," "You're So Nice I Will Kiss You On the Bones," "You're welcome!."
    - Multiple (Box 9, Folder 12)
      "Day one flight of a mind," "Mad," "Phone Number Written on a Leaf," "Silver Bracelet," "Hairs," "Hiding Inside the Good Girl," "Whiplash," and "We're driving south in Oregon in a car filled with stories," 4 typewritten pages. "Famous," "My Uncle's Favorite Coffee Shop," "The Story, Around the Corner," and "Trying to Name What Doesn't Change," 3 printout pages. "Five unpublished tiny poems for my Daddy," "My Immigrant Dad, On Voting," "Daddy Help Us!," "Daddy Died But," and "C'Mon Daddy," 4 typewritten pages. "He wants to, then," "Following the Track," and "Coats on the Bed," 5 typewritten pages, (3 leaves). "The House in the Heart," "With the Greeks," "Office 337, Wheeler Hall, Berkeley," "One Island," Catalogue Army," "Leo," and "Trying to Name What Doesn't Change," 7 typewritten mimeo pages. "I move inside the slow breathing," "We have traveled, we have been to other countries," ""What are you doing in that corner?," "To be continuously moving things around," "Meditation," "The old man stood in his suit and said," "Banana Fritter City," "I never knew it would hurt so much to get free," and "I wish that someday you would not be so full of wishes," 11 handwritten and typewritten mimeo pages.
    - Multiple (Box 9, Folder 13)
      "In memory, Al Mueller, Mueller's Organic Farm, Ferguson, Missouri", "From Earth," "Job," "The Mind of Squash," "Shade," "Tether," "Junk," "I Was Thinking of Poems," "What Happened to Everybody," 2 copies of each, 18 printout pages. "Knitting, Crocheting, Sewing…," "Birthday," "Faces Coming Out of Carnegie Hall," and "Salmon River in the Rain," 5 printout pages. "Leaving Him," "Violin," "Frontier," and "What She Was Doing at Home," 1 typewritten page. "Little Blanco River," "I Don't Want to Scare You," "Watching You When You're Not Looking," "Alchemy of the Heart," and "Coming Up for Air," 4 typewritten pages with extensive reader comments. "Messages From Everyone," "Who's Rich?" 2 color photocopies with illustrations. "Money," "Tony," "Always Bring a Pencil," "Simple Tastes," "The Teachers Introduce Themselves Around a Table," "Lag," "White Hair," "The Difficult Life of a Leaf in Tokyo-Yokohama." Last page titled "Small Poems from Japan" and includes "The Crickets Welcome Me to Japan" and "Morito Beach," 6 printout pages, corrected. "On Counting Chickens," "The Single Thing that Draws," "Oats," "We have traveled, we have been to other countries," 2 typewritten pages. "On the Canadian National Railroad," "Sometimes if You Stir the Water Around It Revives Them," "Magician," "Walking Down Blanco Road at Midnight," "Parking Lot," "Redwood Trees," "When I Was Little & There Was Not This Ache," and "Learning How to Eat," 9 handwritten pages. "Our Daily Conversations," "Good Morning I Am an American Shut Up," "Why the Babysitter Cried," 6 typewritten pages.
    - Multiple (Box 9, Folder 14)
      "Poetry by Naomi Shihab Nye," includes "Voices," "For the 500th Dead Palestinian, Ibtisam Bozieh," "If God Won't Take Me, Why Won't the Devil?," "Making a Fist," "Shoulders," "Morning Paper, Society Page," "Famous," "Texas, the First Time," and "What Is Supposed to Happen," 2 typewritten pages. "Poetry Reading on Wednesday, February 11, 1987," a selection of 10 poems from Yellow Glove, including "The Gardener," "Looking for the Cat Grave," "Telling the Story," "What is Given, What Is Not Given," "The Use of Fiction," "Two Countries," "Jerusalem," "When the Flag is Raised – for Judith McPheron," "Rain," and "Dew." 2 typewritten pages. "The Porch of Mr. Laguna," "Teacher, Teacher," "Sometimes the Indians," and "At my 20th high school reunion," 4 printout pages. "Shoulders," "How to Paint a Donkey," "Famous," "Rebellion Against the North Side," "The Flying Cat," "Rain," "The Mother Writes to the Murderer: A Letter," "The Little Brother Poem," and "One Boy Told Me," 2 typewritten pages. "Sky Pie Written in Houston Traffic," "I guess I'll just do what I can see," "God Bless You Little Old Nowhere Man on the Corner," "While on a Trip to Florida," "Sequel to Even When I'm Not With You," "For Stephen Foster," "Those Coming In and Those Coming Out," "I can imagine being old and dying inside," "My Protest Poem (No Belligerence, Just Fact)," "Protest Song #2," "A Letter to My Love Who is Far Away Down the Same Coast," "Long," 11 handwritten pages with corrections. "Thinking of an Island Far Away," "On My Father's 65th Birthday," and "Two Boys and a Hose in May," 3 handwritten pages with corrections. "Two Pages of Moments," circa 1974, "The Hair," "Monday," "While Sitting in My William Blake Class," "So You Are Going to be a Writer," "The Same Old Songs," "Upon Visiting Your Room for the Second-to-Last Time," "Our Job," "New Skills," 2 typewritten pages. "Two Pictures – for Jane," circa 1968, "Be Willing – In Celebration of the Life of Jane Browne Bove," 1 printout page with handwritten note. "The United States is Not the World," "Our Best Selves," and "Wee Path," 4 printout pages. "An Unobscure Poem for William Blake," circa 1972, "We have traveled, we have been to other countries," "Dying," "On Counting Chickens," "Soft Returns," "Pockets," and "So You Are Going to be a Writer," 3 typewritten pages. "The Whole Self," "The Shopper," "Over the Fence," and "Making a Fist," photocopy of 1 typewritten page.
    - Groupings (Box 10, Folder 1)
      "The Ambassador," "St. Louis," "Arabic Coffee" and others, translated into German, 30 printout pages. "At Otto's Place" and others, 8 typewritten pages. "Catalogue Army" and others, poems from Yellow Glove. 4 typewritten pages. "Madison Street" and others, 15 typewritten pages.
    - Groupings (Box 10, Folder 2)
      "Making a Fist" and others, 15 typewritten pages, some with corrections. "Our World" and others, 22 printout pages. "Sleep's Little House" and others, 4 typewritten and printout pages. "Thank you" and others, 29 typewritten and printout pages, includes 2 songs.
    - Groupings (Box 10, Folder 3)
      "Just Call Me Aziz," "Everything in Our World Did Not Seem to Fit," "My Life Before America Had No Toilet Tissue," "We Did Not Have Drinking Water in the Middle of the Ocean," "Is Misery Near Kansas, I Asked," "Many Asked Me Not to Forget Them," "A Kansas Preacher Called Me Muscleman," "I Hate It, I Love It," "When One is So Far from Home, Life is a Mix of Fact & Fiction," "Being Back with the Family is Quite Wonderful but Terribly Exhausting," "Member of the Tribe," "Fifty Years Since I Prayed or Thought in Arabic."
    - Groupings (Box 10, Folder 4)
      "Two Early Poems from Modern Poetry Studies" and others, 106 typewritten, published and photocopied, and handwritten pages.
    - World Poetry Portfolio #37 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      "Problems," "Longfellow's Bed," "Chico Brothers Fruit & Vegetable #1," Chico Brothers Fruit & Vegetable #2," "Standing Back," "Room for You Here," "Thinking About Anything," "Enthusiast," "Remember Me."
    - Groupings (Box 10, Folder 6)
      Poet Profile, "In Her Own Words," "Say These Things," "Blue Bucket."
    - Spanish Translations (Box 10, Folder 7)
      Nye poems translated into Spanish, all previously published in collections except "So Far," 7 printout pages. Includes "So Far," "The Travelling Onion," "The Man Who Makes Brooms," "The Uses of Fiction," "Seven Mile Ranch, Comstock, Texas," "The Art of Disappearing," "So Much Happiness"
    - Fragments (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Notes (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Oversized (Box 49, Folder 8)
      "Dignity Digs Differences," 5 OS pages, handwritten with corrections and annotations.
    - Oversized (Box 49, Folder 9)
      "Once," 1 oversized page, handwritten. Includes prose piece "A Natural Thursday," handwritten with corrections.
    - Oversized (Box 49, Folder 10)
      "One of a Kind," 1 oversized page, hand written with corrections and annotations.
    - Oversized (Box 49, Folder 11)
      "A True Arab," Newspaper publication.
    - Oversized (Box 54, Folder 2)
      "Eight Years Ago."
    - Oversized (Box 54, Folder 3)
      "An incredibly sad-feeling time."
  - Monographs-Poetry, circa 1977-2018
    - Different Ways to Pray, 1980
      - Naomi's copy, circa 1977 (Box 10, Folder 10)
        Many poems include duplicates, multiple drafts, corrections, and notations of submission or publication.
    - Yellow Glove: Poems, 1986
      - Manuscript, 1981-1984, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - Manuscript, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - Manuscript, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - Manuscript, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Twenty Other Worlds, unpublished, circa 1989
      - Corrected draft (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Mint, 1991
      - Manuscripts (Box 11, Folder 1)
        Printout draft of an introduction and most poems in final collection, with minor corrections; includes "With the Children at the River," one handwritten page with corrections. Printout drafts, with page numbers and minor corrections.
      - Proofs (Box 11, Folder 2)
        Includes proof sent from Judith with correspondence; major corrections and annotations by Judith and Nye.
    - Travel Alarm, 1993
      - Manuscript (Box 11, Folder 3)
        With writer and editor corrections and annotations
    - Fuel, 1998
      - Uncorrected galley (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Photocopies (Box 11, Folder 5)
        Cover and table of contents, notations on poem "One Boy Told Me."
    - Come With Me: Poems for a Journey, 2000
      - Proposed poems (Box 11, Folder 6)
        Printout drafts with editor's notes.
      - Printout drafts (Box 11, Folder 7)
        Draft with light notations, 2 copies. Printout draft, "To Virginia," with some annotation.
      - Draft and Mockups (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - Illustrations, 1996-1997, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
        3 color printouts, 10 photographic slides, examples from magazines.
    - 19 Varieties of Gazelle: Poems of the Middle East, 2002
      See also Editor's Correspondence, 2001-2002 for correspondence with Virginia Duncan, including drafts of introduction.
      - Notes (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - Selections (Box 11, Folder 11)
        List of poem titles, publisher agreement form, publisher public comments, poems "Steps," "19 Varieties of Gazelle," and "The Tray."
      - Introduction, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 12)
        "Flinn, On the Bus," 3 printout drafts with corrections and annotations.
      - Clean draft (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Corrected draft, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 14)
        Includes faxes with editor Virginia Duncan and some notes.
      - Correspondence, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 15)
      - Cover proofs, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - A Maze Me: Poems for Girls, 2005
      Correspondence including draft of introduction in Editor Correspondence, Feb.-March 2004.
      - Notes (Box 11, Folder 17)
      - Draft (Box 11, Folder 18)
        80 pages.
      - Review and excerpt, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Honeybee: Poems and Short Prose, 2008
      - Draft (Box 11, Folder 20)
      - Proof (Box 11, Folder 21)
        With annotations by Nye. 173 pages.
    - Transfer, 2011
      - Late draft (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Voices in the Air: Poems for Listeners, 2018
      - Notes and drafts (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Draft (Box 12, Folder 3)
        With annotations by Nye.
  - Monographs-Edited Poetry, 1982-2010
    - This Same Sky: A Collection of Poems from Around the World, 1992
      - Introduction drafts and poems (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Post-publication, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - The Tree Is Older Than You Are: A Bilingual Gathering of Poems & Stories from Mexico with Paintings by Mexican Artists, 1995
      - Contributors and contracts, 1992-1994 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - Contributors correspondence, 1992-1995 (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - Draft, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - Mexico, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 9)
        Travel itinerary and notes.
      - Research, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - What Have You Lost?, 1998
      - Poems (Box 12, Folder 11)
        With annotations.
      - Cover art (Box 12, Folder 12)
        Ideas and notes.
    - The Space Between Our Footsteps, 1998
      Note that correspondence and poems related to The Space Between Our Footsteps, 1998, can be found in Series III: Correspondence, under various correspondents.
      - Submissions, poems, and correspondence, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - I Feel a Little Jumpy Around You: A Book of Her Poems and His Poems Collected in Pairs, 1999
      Includes contributor list and multiple drafts removed from Editor's Correspondence.
      - Notes and ideas (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - List of contributors (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - Tentative Table of Contents (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Draft (Box 13, Folder 4)
        141 pages
      - Draft (Box 13, Folder 5)
        In sections